

senior software engineer / site reliability engineer

Location: San Francisco, CA

Phone: +14159373151

Email: chad@horohoe.email

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/

chad-horohoe

Profile

Senior DevOps Engineer with over 10 years of experiences that can aid nearly any organization--for-profit, non-profit, even government--as they aim to scale. I've built things for small teams of engineers in a single location and I've also served traffic to hundreds of millions of users across the globe. Always striving to learn more and continue to excel in my line of work.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer, ASAPP, Inc; San Francisco, CA – June 2018 to December 2019

- · Lead migration from github.com to Github Enterprise for 460 repositories
- · Implemented vendor-provided intrusion detection system (IDS) in staging and production
- · Crafted and gained approval for company-wide AWS resource tagging policy
- Provided consultation for infrastructure & architectural needs of engineering teams
- With security, transitioned access IAM Users to team-based IAM Roles for 200 engineers
- Provisioned new and documented existing infrastructure using Terraform

Senior Software Engineer, Wikimedia Foundation; San Francisco, CA - January 2016 to June 2018

- Orchestrated efficient large-scale production software deployments, including debugging and troubleshooting post-deploy, solving technical issues quickly and accurately
- · Led development initiative to rethink deployment pipeline and tooling
- · Managed Release Engineering team as needed

Software Engineer, Wikimedia Foundation; San Francisco, CA – June 2010 to January 2016

- · Managed code deployment processes and third party releases for MediaWiki
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable replacement for aging in-house fulltext search engine
- Reviewed PHP code across multiple subsystems, providing actionable feedback and learning opportunities for fellow engineers

Project Configuration Management Analyst, Capital One; Richmond, VA - July 2009 to October 2010

- Administered code repositories CentOS-based servers, including branch management
- Processed 20-30 daily code migrations between environments

IT Intern, City of Richmond Department of IT; Richmond, VA - December 2006 to October 2008

- · Granted and revoked access to end users from all departments across various City infrastructure
- · Participated in internal security audits for PCI compliance
- · Maintained intranet and internet websites

Education

Virginia Commonwealth University; Richmond, VA - BS in Information Systems, 2012

Skills

Python, Git, Terraform/HCL, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Puppet, bare metal, scaling, Redis, Elasticsearch, Mysql, Java, PHP, Jenkins, CircleCl

(references available upon request)